A Guide to the Fort Hunt High School Collection, 1968-1984
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Fort Hunt High School Collection, 1968-1984
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 11-17
0.5 linear feet
The Fort Hunt High School Collection contains 0.5 linear feet, spans the years 1968-1984, and consists of issues of the school’s newspaper “Frontline” and the school’s literary magazine “Turret”.
Fort Hunt High School
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Patricia Hardesty donated the collection of 1968-1971 newspapers and literary magazines in September 2018. Jeff Clark, FCPS donated the 1976-1984 newspapers which were found in a drawer by a journalism teacher at West Springfield High School in April 2019.
Historical and Biographical Information
In 1960, Fairfax County planned for the building of a new high school in Fort Hunt to serve the growing population of the area. Local architect Dwight G. Chase & Associates designed a large high school to accommodate a student population of 1,200 with future expansion for 2,000 additional students. Construction on the $2.5 million school started in the fall of 1961. The school, located at 8428 Fort Hunt Road, opened in September 1963 and operated for 22 years. It closed in 1985 due to declining enrolment, and Fort Hunt combined with Groveton High School to form West Potomac High School. The old Fort Hunt High School is now home to Carl Sandburg Middle School.
Scope and Content
The Fort Hunt High School Collection contains 0.5 linear feet, spans the years 1968-1984, and consists of issues of the school’s newspaper “Frontline” and the school’s literary magazine “Turret”. The newspaper covered school news, sports, special activities, and student opinions, and the literary magazine provided students with an outlet to publish their creative writings.
Series 1: "Turret" Literary Magazine, 1970, Box 1
This series contains issues of “Turret”, Fort Hunt High School’s literary magazine. Students published poetry, art, photographs, and creative writings in this student-produced periodical.
Series 2: "Frontline" Newspaper, 1968-1984, Box 1
This series contains issues of “Frontline”, Fort Hunt High School’s school newspaper. Students in the journalism class wrote the articles and put together the paper. The format of the paper changed over the years ranging from tabloid to broadsheet. The newspaper covered school news, sports, special activities, and student opinions. Also included in this series is "The Last Gasp", the farewell newspaper for the Senior Class of 1971.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax County Public Schools; Fort Hunt High School (Alexandria, Va.); Student newspapers and periodicals
Container List
- Series 1: "Turret" Literary Magazine, 1970
  - "Turret" Freshman Issue Vol. 7, No. 1, January 1970, 1970 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Turret" Sophomore Issue Vol. 7, No. 2, January 1970, 1970 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Turret" Junior Issue Vol. 7, No. 3, January 1970, 1970 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Turret" Senior Issue Vol. 7, No. 4, January 1970, 1970 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Turret" Vol. 7, No. 5 Spring 1970, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 2: "Frontline" Newspaper, 1968-1984
  - "Frontline", 1968 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Frontline", 1969 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Frontline", 1970 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Frontline", 1971 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Frontline", 1971 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Last Gasp" [Senior farewell newspaper], 1971 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Frontline", 1971 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Frontline", 1976 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Frontline" [2 copies], 1976 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Frontline", 1976 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Frontline", 1977 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Frontline" [2 copies], 1977 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Frontline", 1977 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Frontline", 1978 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Frontline", 1978 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Frontline", 1978 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Frontline", 1979 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Frontline", 1979 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Frontline", 1980 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Frontline", 1980 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Frontline" Magazine, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Frontline", 1981 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Frontline", 1981 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Frontline", 1982 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Frontline", 1982 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Frontline", 1982 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Frontline", 1982 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Frontline", 1983 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Frontline", 1983 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Frontline", 1984 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Frontline", 1984 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Frontline", 1984 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 37)